hey everyone welcome back to our Channel
I am back with another interesting topic
in the Tosca automation playlist
continuing with our obstacle topic we
are in our fourth obstacle so let's see
what this obstacle is all about it is
called two times uh and what we have to
do is we have to create a automation
test step where it can click on this
button two times in a row
so when you click on this particular
button first time it is Click me to X
and the second time it changes to click
me once more okay and when you click on
this again then uh this particular
obstacle is completed so that's what we
need to do uh let's go ahead and get
started
now let's create a module for this
particular control so let's scan this
application and record these modules
so let's go ahead and go to the scan
application
and then scan this application
and let's have a look at this particular
control okay so here what you can see
is
this particular control is unique okay
so it is Tosca is able to identify this
using the different properties and the
two properties which it is taking is the
ID here okay and the tag which is a and
here it is r d underscore some random
number
now uh let's go ahead and click so we
are not going to save this okay because
I want to show you what happens when we
click on this once and then now if we go
ahead and scan this again
okay and now if we go ahead and select
this particular control this time also
it is unique because it is also able to
identify using the properties but you
will see that uh the ID right has
changed so it's a different ID for this
particular control now so once we click
on this the later part of or the
numerical part of the ID is changing for
the same control so we need to handle
that in our modules right and the way we
can do this is using regular expression
uh so that we can handle this Dynamic
part of the ID right so what we can do
simply here is we can
put a star which stands for a regular
expression for one or more occurrences
right so any numerical digits uh would
be handled by this regular expression no
matter if it changes right or it remains
same it will work both ways
so uh this we can do the ID we can
change that right and now uh it doesn't
matter if the ID changes or it should
still work
so let's go ahead and save this module
now
and we are going to come here and we are
going to rename this module first
okay
and then we are going to create a test
case
so that we can see how it works right so
let's go ahead and create a test case
here I'm going to rename this again
and then we are going to drag this
particular module here
and we are going to click on this so
again we'll use the x value here
and we are going to name this step
okay so click
once
and then again we are going to drag this
module another time because we have to
click it two times right so we are going
to rename this step again click twice
okay and then we are going to click on
this particular
control okay so ideally it should click
uh two times even though the ID is
changing because of our regular
expression in the module properties okay
so I will change the workstate to
completed
and then on the application I need to go
back to the initial state right so come
back to the screen where it shows click
me to X okay so now I'm going to execute
this test case and see if it still works
okay so yeah as you can see it was able
to click the link two times and the
obstacle was completed
so using regular expressions in your
model properties you can handle Dynamic
elements which have got properties which
are changing dynamically
that's all for this particular video if
you have any questions then please leave
it in the comments
if you like this video then please
subscribe to our Channel
thanks for watching and I will see you
in the next video